Guide to the Archives Union File (AUF), Section 3: Boxes 127-191
Archives Union File (AUF), Section 3: Boxes 127-191
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: Structure and functioning of the ILGWU, 1947; Publication (Box 188, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: Understanding basic problems, 1949; Publication (Box 188, Folder 8)
    Notes: Reprinted from the Federationist, AF of L, Nov. 1949. 2 copies
  - Item 5: Why union education?, 1948; Publication (Box 188, Folder 8)
    Notes: Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, vol. 92, no. 3, 1948. 2 copies
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Workers education, the dream and the reality, 1948; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
    Notes: Reprinted from Workers Education Bureau News Letter, July-August, 1948
  - Item 2: Workers education in a troubled world, 1949; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: A union at play, 1947; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
    Notes: Reprinted from American Federationist
  - Item 4: Education in a troubled world, 1948; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
    Author: Henry David
    Notes: Panel discussion, held February 28, 1948, at the I.L.G.W.U. studio (pt. 1-2) [2 copies - pt.1]
  - Item 5: Everybody sings, 1951; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: The ILGWU legal department, 1948-1949 (Box 188, Folder 9)
    Author: Morris P. Glushien
  - Item 7: The Negro's stake in the future of American industry, 1948; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: The role of government: discussion ... at the ILGWU Educational-Recreational Center, February 1949, Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
    Author: Julius Bloch
  - Item 9: UNESCO: its objectives and how to implement them, 1949; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
  - Item 10: Who makes public opinion?: will the New Deal be expanded?: social security in a democratic society?: panel discussion, an outline, March 26, 1949; Publication (Box 188, Folder 9)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: It's your law, too!, Publication (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Report of Educational Dept. ILGWU [June 1, 1948 to May 31, 1950], 1948-1950 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: The women in America., 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 4: Training for trade union service: How the New York Dress Joint Board works, 1936-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 5: Training for trade union service: Labor capital relations, 1936-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Training for trade union service: Structure and function of the New York Cloakworkers' Joint Bd., 1936-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Training for trade union service: The ILGWU Joint Board of Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Reefer Makers'., 1936-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Training for trade union service: The ILGWU management engineering dept., 1936-1956 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Why workers' education?, Publication (Box 189, Folder 1)
    Notes: Reprinted from Souvenir Booklet of the The Western Summer School for Workers. Copy 2
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Day by day at the First Midwest Region Institute, ILGWU, School for Workers, Univ. of Wisconsin, 1951; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Notes: Class schedule. Copy 2
  - Item 2: Estructura y funcionamiento de la ILGWU, 1950; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Facts about the United States labor force as of 1947, Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Notes: Poster
  - Item 4: How the Politburo Thinks, 1951; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Author: Leo Calvin Rosten
  - Item 5: The Great revolt of nineteen ten, Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Notes: Song lyrics
  - Item 6: The history of the ILGWU in song and poem, 1957; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Notes: a sequence of narrative, group singing and poetry reading for use in meetings
  - Item 7: The story of the ILGWU, 1951; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Author: Max D. Danish
  - Item 8: The Triangle fire, Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: The Uprising of the twenty thousand, Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: With these hands, 1951; Publication (Box 189, Folder 2)
    Notes: Motion Picture advertisement
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: No need for regimentation, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
    Notes: JUSTICE articles
  - Item 2: Higher wages can keep economy level, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Item 3: New policies may bring unemployment, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Item 4: After peace - depression or prosperity?, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: This is the union of the Garment Workers, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Item 6: Unions bargain on equal terms, Publication (Box 189, Folder 3)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Justice, 1953; Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
    Author: ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union)
    Notes: May 1, 1953 (page three). 2 copies
  - Item 2: Panel discussion - Does planning against a depression interfere with personal freedom?, 1953; Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Report - June, 1951-May, 1953, Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Trends and prospects Women's Garment Industry 1950-1953, Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: Union members learn to live and lead, 1953; Publication (Box 189, Folder 4)
    Notes: Reprinted from the 20th Anniv. Yearbook of Adult Education, published by the New York Adult Educ. Council, Inc.,
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: AFL News-Reporter, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Notes: vol.3:no.53
  - Item 2: Garment workers 'welfare unionism', 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprint Current History. 2 copies
  - Item 3: How lucky is my social security number?, 1945; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Author: Goodman Block
  - Item 4: Manual for education committees, I.L.G.W.U., Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Item 5: Newsletter #11 - Yak-Yak, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Panel discussion - How is our troubled changing world reflected in the arts - the novel - theatre - movies - television and paintings?, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Item 7: Security and insecurity Panel discussion, 1955; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: The constant catfish, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from Adult Education for Everybody
  - Item 9: The Library helps labor, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from ALA Bulletin, October, 1954
  - Item 10: The Masses and current literature: a summary analysis, 1955; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Author: Stern, Bernard H.
  - Item 11: The McCarthy balance sheet, 1954; Publication (Box 189, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from the New York World-Telegram
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: A labor view of vocational education, Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
    Notes: Reprinted from IUD Digest
  - Item 2: Developing Union Educational Committees, 1956; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
    Notes: Reprinted from AFL-CIO Education News & Views, Nov. 1956
  - Item 3: flyer about Life Class (an ILGWU JUSTICE feature), Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: For you too! - Central Classes, 1958-1959 (Box 189, Folder 6)
    Notes: Oct. 1958-May 1959
  - Item 5: From division to unity: AFL and CIO: the position of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: from the report of the General Executive Board to the 29th convention ..., 1956; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: Ideas and suggestions for Union Education, Summary report of discussions, 1956; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: Operation ILGWU Education, 1956; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
    Notes: Presentation made to Atlantic City Convention of the ILGWU
  - Item 8: The history of the ILGWU in song and poem: a sequence of narrative, group singing and poetry reading for use in meetings and institutes to present the main events of the Union's development., 1957; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 9: Training for Union service - Starting a local union educational program, 1956; Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
  - Item 10: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1953-1956, Publication (Box 189, Folder 6)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Adult labor education in a troubled world: a guide for teachers, 1958; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: Do schools teach the facts of union life?, 1959; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
    Notes: Industrial Bulletin, January, 1959
  - Item 3: Education recommendations and reports of 30th ILGWU convention, May, 1959, Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: Labor education in Britain shows change, Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 5: Newsletter, 1958; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 6: Report to the Social Security Commission of the Garment Industry, St. Louis, Missouri, 1947; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
    Author: Ross Garrett and Associates
  - Item 7: Seventh Avenue; road to improved labor-management relations., 1958; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
  - Item 8: Structure and functioning of the ILGWU, 1959; Publication (Box 189, Folder 7)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1956-1959: report presented by General Executive Board to the ILGWU Atlantic City Convention, May, 1959, Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1959-1962: report presented by General Executive Board to the ILGWU Atlantic City Convention, May, 1962, Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 3: We kept our faith; a memorial to our Triangle victims, 1936; Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 4: British unions are now part of social order by Ralph K. Reuter., 1960; Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: Equal opportunity union made, 1962; Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 6: Medal for a union, Fifty years of the ILGWU Union Health Center, 1964; Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: Philosophy of workers' education, 1948; Publication (Box 189, Folder 8)
    Notes: Reprinted from Industrial and Labor Relations Review, Cornell Univ., vol. 1, no. 4, July, 1948
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Education department report to general executive board, Carrillon Hotel, Miami Beach, Florida (Jan. 30, Dec. 14), 1967; Publication (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: That reminds me. Jokes and stories for use by Union Organizers and papers, Publication (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: The ILGWU management-Engineering Dept., 1965; Publication (Box 190, Folder 1)
    Notes: Training-for-trade-union-service
  - Item 4: The story of the I.L.G.W.U., a radio play in six episodes, 1930-1939 (Box 190, Folder 1)
    Author: Florence Lasser
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Citizen of the Union: here's how to sell what we sew, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Citizen of the Union: our rights and responsibilities, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Citizen of the Union: the Union, what, why, how, where, when., Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Citizen of the Union: why workers must vote, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Education Dept. report to the General Executive Board, New York City, Mar. 14, 1966, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Justice, 1975; Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
    Notes: v.57:no.9-10 (1975). 2 copies
  - Item 7: Medal for a union, Fifty years of the ILGWU Union Health Center, 1964; Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Trends and prospects in the women's garment industry, 1965-1968, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Trends and prospects in the women's garment industry, 1968-1971, Publication (Box 190, Folder 2)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Where do we stand in the world today?, Publication (Box 190, Folder 3)
    Author: International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Educational Dept.
  - Item 2: Why workers' education? ..., Publication (Box 190, Folder 3)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Congressional Record, 1963; Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
    Notes: vol.109:no.65 (1963:May 2)
  - Item 2: ILG Health Center: the first 50 years, 1964; Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Justice, 1964; Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
    Notes: v.46:no.11 (1964:June 1)
  - Item 4: Reprinted from Proceedings of the Nat'l. time and motion study clinic, 1945; Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Item 5: The Garment industry medical center, 1947; Publication (Box 190, Folder 4)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Industrial vs. Craft unionism, 1936; Publication (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Item 2: Manifesto issued by the General Exec. Bd. To the Cloakmakers and Dressmakers, 1928; Publication (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Twenty-fifth Anniv. Of the Presidency of David Dubinsky and ILGWU Progress, 1957; Publication (Box 190, Folder 5)
    Notes: Program. 2 copies
  - Item 4: Win the cold war, preserve the peace; declaration adopted by the 27th (50th anniversary) convention, Atlantic City, N.J., May 23-June 1, 1950., Publication (Box 190, Folder 5)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: A letter to the delegates of the seventeenth biennial convention of the International ladies' garment workers union from the General executive board., 1924; Publication (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1944-1947: report presented by General Executive Board to the ILGWU Cleveland Convention, June, 1947., Publication (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Item 3: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1947-1950: report presented by General Executive Board to the ILGWU Atlantic City Convention, May, 1950., Publication (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Item 4: Trends and prospects, women's garment industry, 1956-1959: report presented by General Executive Board to the ILGWU Atlantic City Convention, May, 1959, Publication (Box 190, Folder 6)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Trends and prospects in the women's garment industry, 1962-1965: report presented by General Executive Board to the 32nd ILGWU Convention, Miami Beach, Florida, May, 1965, Publication (Box 190, Folder 7)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: 25th Anniversary Reunion, ILGWU Student Fellowship, symposium., 1945; Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: How the garment unions licked the communists, 1947; Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
    Author: J. C. Rich
  - Item 3: So it didn't work (a comedy in one act), Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
    Author: Joseph Lawrence
  - Item 4: Stick to your union bunch or you'll get skinned!..., Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 5: Sunrise - a labor drama in three scenes, Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 6: That reminds me. Jokes and stories for use by Union Organizers and papers, Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 7: Where do we stand in the world today?, Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Item 8: Workers' wives, 1926; Publication (Box 190, Folder 8)
    Notes: Reprinted from 'Labor Age', issue of November, 1926
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Negro members of the ILGWU, Publication (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: The ILGWU story, Publication (Box 191, Folder 1)
    Notes: Paper/report
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Excerpts from the section on health and welfare funds in the General Executive Report to the 31st Convention(annual), 1962; Publication (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Financial report of the health, welfare retirement and supplementary unemployment-severance funds, 1961; Publication (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Health guidance for participants in the mobile health survey, 1965; Publication (Box 191, Folder 2)
    Author: James Bloom
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Health and welfare services: bringing more happiness and security to the men and women of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: based upon a report for the years 1950, 1951, and 1952, Publication (Box 191, Folder 3)
    Author: International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. General Executive Board. Health and Welfare Committee.
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Health services for the membership of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, 1950; Publication (Box 191, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: The thread of life; ILGWU health and welfare services, 1956; Publication (Box 191, Folder 4)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Health and welfare funds, 1948; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Author: Leo Price
  - Item 2: Health and welfare in the Ladies' Garment Industry, 1948; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: History in the making, 1948; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Author: Max Meyer
  - Item 4: ILGWU Health and Welfare Programs, Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Notes: Advertisement
  - Item 5: L.A. Union Health Center ILGWU, 1953; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Item 6: Union health center of the ILGWU, 1953; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Notes: Reprinted from Industrial Medicine and Surgery, Oct. 1953
  - Item 7: Financial report of the health, welfare retirement and supplementary unemployment-severance funds, 1964; Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Item 8: Health and Welfare, Publication (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Notes: Packet of assorted forms
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Justice, 1960; Publication (Box 191, Folder 6)
    Notes: v. 42, no. 11-12 (1960)
  - Item 2: Justice, 1966; Publication (Box 191, Folder 6)
    Notes: v. 48, no. 22 (1966)
  - Item 3: The New York Times, 1959; Publication (Box 191, Folder 6)
    Notes: May 17, 1959 (Advertisement)
  - Item 4: Women's Wear Daily, 1950; Publication (Box 191, Folder 6)
    Notes: Tues., May 23, 1950
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Signature of 450,000, 1965; Publication (Box 191, Folder 7)
    Notes: This publicatin is a prersentation of the 65th Anniversay Convention of the ILGWU, Miami Beach, FL, May 1965. 2 copies
  - Item 2: The Electrical Workers' Journal, 1950; Publication (Box 191, Folder 7)
    Notes: 1950 February
  - Item 3: The History of the ILGWU: an outline, 1934; Publication (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Item 4: The story of progress among the women's garment makers, 1929; Publication (Box 191, Folder 7)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The New York Times, 1959; Publication (Box 191, Folder 8)
    Notes: May 17, 1959 (Advertisement). Copy 2
  - Item 2: The story of the I.L.G.W.U., a radio play in six episodes, 1939; Publication (Box 191, Folder 8)
- ILGWU (International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union), Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Homework 1909, Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: If you don't come in Sunday don't come in Monday, Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: ILGWU guide on agreement provisions, standards and enforcement, 1965; Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 4: Journey into ILGWU History, Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
    Notes: Reprinted from JUSTICE
  - Item 5: The Ladies' Garment Worker in the history and shop, 1942; Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 6: The outside system of production in the women's garment industry in the New York market, 1951; Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 7: The position of the International ladies' garment workers' union in relation to CIO and AFL, 1934-1938, chronicled in documents and records., Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 8: The story of progress among the women's garment makers, 1929; Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
  - Item 9: The Triangle Fire, 1952; Publication (Box 191, Folder 9)
    Author: William Z. Berman
    Notes: Submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements: Econ 115 at Brothers College, Drew Univ., Madison, NJ, Nov. 20, 1952